Campus Action; Records apap164
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Events, 1992-2004; Undated; 3
  - "Uniting To Challenge Racism", Conference, Conference Schedule, 2004
  - "Uniting To Challenge Racism", Conference, Email Recruiting Invitation, 2004
  - "Uniting To Challenge Racism", Conference, Panel Introduction Sheet, 2004
  - "Uniting To Challenge Racism", Conference, Racism Conference Email, 2004
- Subject Files, 1993-2003; Undated; 4
  Arranged by topic.
  The materials in this series relate to issues of interest to Campus Action. These files contain collected publications, news clippings, articles, fliers, webpages, correspondence, and other materials related to the individual topics of interest. Particularly well documented in the paper records of Campus Action is the issue of date rape on university campuses. Campus Action's opposition to the wars in Afghanistan and Iraq is particularly well documented in the electronic records, with related defenses of detainees in the civil rights and racism sections. Represented here are also materials created by other campus groups that worked with Campus Action including the Black and Latino Network; Gay, Lesbian and Straight Education Network; and the NETWORK student organization. The case of Ali Yaghi is also documented in the electronic records. Yaghi, an Albany resident and owner of a pizza shop, was arrested just days after 9/11. He was detained on the basis of a tip by a passerby, who claimed to have heard Yaghi making anti-American statements. Yaghi was detained for months and though eventually cleared of all allegations related to terrorism, he was deported to his native Jordan because of his immigration status.
  - Environment, Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Feminism, National Organization for Women, Publications List, Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Human Rights, Kensington Welfare Rights Union, Article, 1998 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Internships, 1993-1995; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Judicial Decisions, News Clippings, 1996-1997 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Lesbian and Gay, AIDS Quilt, 1998 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Lesbian and Gay, Correspondence, 1998 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Lesbian and Gay, Equality Begins At Home Campaign, Fliers, Contact List, 1989 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Lesbian and Gay, Gay, Lesbian And Straight Education Network (GLSEN), 2001; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Lesbian and Gay, Lesbian, Gay, And Bisexual Alliance, 1994; 1996 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Lesbian and Gay, Peer Education, Articles, Correspondence, 1998 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Lesbian and Gay, Pride Agenda, 1998 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Lesbian and Gay, Pride Alliance Network, Correspondence, 2005 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Lesbian and Gay, Pride Connection, Contact Lists, 1997-1998; 2001-2002; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Lesbian and Gay, Queer Network, 1998; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Lesbian and Gay, Resources, 1998; 2001; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Lesbian and Gay, Status of Key Bills, 1997-1998 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Lesbian and Gay, "Understanding the Issues Facing Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Transgendered Survivors of Sexual Assault Who Struggle with Mental Illness, Resource Packet, 1998 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - "Organizing College Campuses Against Dating Abuse", National Resource Center on Domestic Violence, 1999 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Peace Internship, Notes, Flier, Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Racism, Anti-Racism Task Force, 1998-1999; 2002; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Racism, Articles, News Clippings, 1997-1998 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Racism, Black and Latino Network, 1993-1997; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Racism, Mock Trial, News Clippings, Biographical Material, 1998; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Racism, Moore Case, Correspondence, News Clippings, Petition, 1997 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Racism, Rally Against Racism, 1996 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - "Sexual Aggression and Acquaintance Rape: A Survey of Union College Students", Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Sexual Assault, Acquaintance Rape, Fliers, Handouts, Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Sexual Assault, Articles, News Clippings, 1993-1996 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Sexual Assault, Contact Lists, 1997; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Sexual Assault, Correspondence, 1994-1995; 1998; 2002-2003; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Sexual Assault, Drugs, Press Releases, Fliers, 1997; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Sexual Assault, Economic Costs of Sexual Violence, Articles, 1995-1996 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Sexual Assault, Educational Material, 1998; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Sexual Assault, Faculty Response, 1997; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Sexual Assault, Feminists United For Action, 2002; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Sexual Assault, Fliers, Leaflets, Pamphlets, 1994-1998; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Sexual Assault, Harassment Log, Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Sexual Assault, Inter-campus Sexual Assault Task Force, 1996-1999 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Sexual Assault, Inter-campus Sexual Assault Task Force, 2005; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Sexual Assault, Lobby Day, Fliers, Mailings, 1996 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Sexual Assault, Media Resources, 1994; 1996; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Sexual Assault, Middle Earth Peer Assistance Program, 1997; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Sexual Assault, Model Policies, 1997-1998; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Sexual Assault, National Organization for Women, Fliers, Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Sexual Assault, Nature of Consent, Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Sexual Assault, NETWORK Student Group, 1998; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - Sexual Assault, Notes, Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - Sexual Assault, Penal Code, Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - Sexual Assault, Policies from Other Campuses, 1996-1997; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - Sexual Assault, President's Task Force for Women's Safety, 1997-1998 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - Sexual Assault, Rape Crisis Center, 1998; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 52)
  - Sexual Assault, Resources, 1992-1997; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 53)
  - Sexual Assault, Role of Men, 1996; 1998; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 54)
  - Sexual Assault, Sexual Assault Reform Act, Legislation, 1997 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 55)
  - Sexual Assault, Sexual Harassment, 1997-1998; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 56)
  - Sexual Assault, Sexually Transmitted Diseases, Fliers, Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 57)
  - Sexual Assault, Siena Work Club, Correspondence, Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 58)
  - Sexual Assault, Stalking, Article, 1997 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 59)
  - Sexual Assault, Statistics, 1998; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 60)
  - Sexual Assault, Student Contacts, 1996-1998; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 61)
  - Sexual Assault, Surveys, 1996; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 62)
  - Sexual Assault, Survivor Resources, 1996; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 63)
  - Sexual Assault, United Council Campus Safety Awareness Manual, 1997 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 64)
  - Sexual Assault, University at Albany Publications, 1997; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 65)
  - Sexual Assault, Violence Against Women Prevention Act, Summary, 1998 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 66)
  - Sexual Assault, Whistlewatch Program, Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 67)
  - Civil Liberties, Ansar Mamood Petition, 2004
  - Civil Liberties, Artists for Social Justice Concert, 2003
  - Civil Liberties, Defense Committee Contacts, 2004
  - Civil Liberties, Draft Brochure, 2004
  - Civil Liberties, Draft Panel Letter, 2004
  - Civil Liberties, Panel Flyer, 2004
  - Civil Liberties, Shokriea Letter, 2003
  - Civil Liberties, The Case of Mumia Abu, 2004
  - Civil Liberties, Yaghi Family Support Committee, Ali Yaghi Paragraph, 2004
  - Civil Liberties, Yaghi Family Support Committee, Ali Yaghi Sample Letters, 2004
  - Civil Liberties, Yaghi Family Support Committee, Background, 2004
  - Civil Liberties, Yaghi Family Support Committee, Contributions, 2004
  - Civil Liberties, Yaghi Family Support Committee, How You Can Help, 2004
  - Civil Liberties, Yaghi Family Support Committee, Index, 2004
  - Civil Liberties, Yaghi Family Support Committee, Links, 2004
  - Civil Liberties, Yaghi Family Support Committee, Prison Abuse Article, 2004
  - Civil Liberties, Yaghi Family Support Committee, Write Letters, 2004
  - Civil Liberties, Yaghi Family Support Committee, Yaghi Family Photograph, 2004
  - Civil Liberties, Yaghi Family Support Committee, Yaghi Family Story, 2004
  - Civil Liberties, Yaghi Family Support Committee, Story By Marty, 2004
  - Environmental, Earth Day Lobby Day, 2004
  - Environmental, Ecologic General Flyer, 2002
  - Environmental, Ecopledge Petition, 2002
  - Environmental, Environmental Action Ideas, 2002
  - Environmental, Environmental Organizations, 2002
  - Environmental, Rain Forest Letter, McNulty, 2001
  - Environmental, Rain Forest Letter, Sweeney, 2001
  - Feminist Network, Action Ideas, 2002
  - Feminist Network, Campus Feminist List, 2003
  - Feminist Network, FAN Flier, 2003
  - Feminist Network, Feminist Network List, 2002
  - Feminist Network, March For Freedom Of Choice, April 25th March Logo, 2003
  - Feminist Network, March For Freedom Of Choice, Protecting A Woman, 2004
  - Feminist Network, Sexual Assault Taskforce, Campaign Against Sexual Assault, 2002
  - Feminist Network, Sexual Assault Taskforce, Model Policies, 2002
  - Feminist Network, SUNY Feminist Constitution, 2002
  - Feminist Network, Use The F Word, 2002
  - Feminist Network, Vox, Bush Agenda Webpage, 2003
  - Feminist Network, Vox, Bush Column SUNY, 2003
  - Feminist Network, Vox, Emergency Contraceptive Pill Column, 2003
  - Feminist Network, Vox, Emergency Contraception Teach-in Webpage, 2003
  - Feminist Network, Vox, Emergency Room Emergency Contraception Webpage, 2003
  - Feminist Network, Vox, Flyer SUNY, 2003
  - Feminist Network, Vox, GAP Flyers, 2003
  - Feminist Network, Vox, Timely Access Webpage, 2003
  - Feminist Network, Vox, Vox Accomplishments, 2003
  - Feminist Network, Vox, Vox Column SUNY, 2003
  - Feminist Network, Vox, Web Material, 2003
  - Internships, Alternative Internship Directory, 2001
  - Internships, Campus Action Intern Sheet, 2002
  - Internships, Campus Action Interns Fall 2003
  - Internships, Campus Action Labor Intern Proposal, 2002
  - Internships, Democracy Matters, Coordinator Job Description, 2001
  - Internships, Democracy Matters, Democracy Matters Intern Ad, 2002
  - Internships, Democracy Matters, Response To New Intern Inquiry, 2001
  - Internships, Elk Intern Contract, 2004
  - Internships, Feminist Organizing Internship Available, 2002
  - Internships, Intern Interview Questions, 2003
  - Internships, Internships Available, 2003
  - Internships, Peace Intern Letter, 2003
  - Internships, Peace Intern Program Brochure, 2003
  - Internships, Peace Intern Recruitment Flyer, 2002
  - Iraq, Iraq Campus Organizing Guide, 2001
  - Iraq, Iraq Speaker Available, 2003
  - Iraq, 2004 March 19
  - Iraq, SUNY Flyer, 2003
  - Korea, Korea Talking Points, 2003
  - Korea, KSN FAQ, 2003
  - Korea, Taskforce, 2003
  - Labor, Labor Intern Proposal, 2003
  - Labor, Take The Pledge, 2003
  - Labor, The Miami Model -- FTAA, 2003
  - Labor, Trading Freedom, 2003
  - Lesbian and Gay, Activist Programs, 2003
  - Lesbian and Gay, Activist SRF, 2003
  - Lesbian and Gay, Article For Paper, 2003
  - Lesbian and Gay, Audre Lord Project Open Letter, 2003
  - Lesbian and Gay, Campus Pride Groups, 2003
  - Lesbian and Gay, First Meeting Agenda, 2003
  - Lesbian and Gay, GLSEN Organizing Guide, 2003
  - Lesbian and Gay, Happy Pins, 2003
  - Lesbian and Gay, Institutional Review Board (IRB), 2003
  - Lesbian and Gay, Learning Contract, 2003
  - Lesbian and Gay, Newsletter, September Pride, 2003
  - Lesbian and Gay, Paper 6, 2003
  - Lesbian and Gay, Pride and Diversity Group, 2003
  - Lesbian and Gay, Pride and Diversity Sign, 2003
  - Lesbian and Gay, Pride and Diversity Sign 2, 2003
  - Lesbian and Gay, Pride and Diversity Survey, 2003
  - Lesbian and Gay, Pride List, 2001
  - Organizing Tips, Act On Convictions, 2001
  - Organizing Tips, Action Ideas, Action Ideas For Environmentalists, 2002
  - Organizing Tips, Action Ideas, Action Ideas To Create Clean, 2002
  - Organizing Tips, Action Ideas, Campaign Against Sexual Assault, 2002
  - Organizing Tips, Action Ideas, Challenge Homophobia, 2002
  - Organizing Tips, Action Ideas, Fight Racism, 2002
  - Organizing Tips, Ant Oppression Tips, 2003
  - Organizing Tips, Anti(ist) Strategies, 2003
  - Organizing Tips, Building A Campaign Questions, 2001
  - Organizing Tips, Building Diverse Coalitions, 2001
  - Organizing Tips, Faculty Advisors Role, 2003
  - Organizing Tips, How To Organize A Campaign, 2002
  - Organizing Tips, How To Plan A Demonstration, 2001
  - Organizing Tips, List Of Demands From A Gender Liberation Conference, 2003
  - Organizing Tips, Overcoming Apathy, 2003
  - Organizing Tips, Rainforest Action Network Student Organizing Handbook, 2004
  - Organizing Tips, Tools For White Guys Who Are Working For Social Change, 2003
  - Peace, "1 Weekend A Month, My Ass" Flyer, 2004
  - Peace, 2005 Military Budget, 2004
  - Peace, Action Ideas For Peace Activists, 2002
  - Peace, April 20th March, Answer April 20th Flier, 2002
  - Peace, April 20th March, April 20th Flier 2, 2002
  - Peace, April 20th March, April 20th Call To Action, 2002
  - Peace, April 20th March, April March On Washington Unity Statement From The, Undated
  - Peace, April 20th March, Capital District Organizing For April 20th Flyer, 2002
  - Peace, April 20th March, Email March info, 2002
  - Peace, April 20th March, March On Washington April 20th, 2002
  - Peace, April 20th March, UPI Story, 2002
  - Peace, Articles, Bush's Regime Change Plan For Iraq, 2002
  - Peace, Articles, Compliant Press, 2002
  - Peace, Articles, Ex-UN Against War, 2002
  - Peace, Articles, Gulf Veterans Oppose, 2002
  - Peace, Articles, Inspect, 2002
  - Peace, Articles, Iraq And Oil, 2002
  - Peace, Articles, Iraq Talking Points, 2002
  - Peace, Articles, Letter From Baghdad, 2003
  - Peace, Articles, Middle East, 2002
  - Peace, Articles, NION New York, 2002
  - Peace, Articles, NOAH and 9-11 NY Times, 2002
  - Peace, Articles, Shaky Legal Grounds, 2002
  - Peace, Articles, Talking Points - Why We Oppose, 2002
  - Peace, Articles, The Case Against War, 2002
  - Peace, Articles, Why U.S. Shouldn't Invade Iraq, 2002
  - Peace, Background Info On The Campaign For A New Foreign Policy, 2004
  - Peace, Before You Enlist, 2003
  - Peace, Call To Action, 2003
  - Peace, Campaign Strategy, 2003
  - Peace, Campus Action Anti-War Network, Action Ideas For Anti-War Work, 2003
  - Peace, Campus Action Anti-War Network, Anti-War Network Email List 2, 2003
  - Peace, Campus Action Anti-War Network, High School Student Peace Activists In The Capital District, 2003
  - Peace, Campus Action Anti-War Network, March 1st Meeting Flier, 2003
  - Peace, Campus Action Anti-War Network, Our Plan To Work Together, 2003
  - Peace, Campus Action Anti-War Network, Reasons People Give For Supporting A Wan In Iraq, 2003
  - Peace, Campus Action Anti-War Network, Reasons To Oppose War On Iraq, 2003
  - Peace, Campus Peace Contacts, 2002
  - Peace, Challenging ROTC Proposal, 2003
  - Peace, Corrected Letter, 2003
  - Peace, Countdown To Kickout SPAN, 2003
  - Peace, Counter Recruitment Expert Oskar Castro, 2004
  - Peace, Endorsements Of The Campaign For A New Foreign Policy By Albany, 2004
  - Peace, February, 15th, March 19th & 20th Text, 2004
  - Peace, FBI Memo Spying On The Peace Movement, 2004
  - Peace, February, 15th, March 19th & 20th Minutes, 2004
  - Peace, Flyer 1, 2003
  - Peace, Gore Vidal, 2003
  - Peace, Intro Email, 2003
  - Peace, Iraq Pledge Of Resistance Legal, 2003
  - Peace, March 19th Siena Gonyo, 2004
  - Peace, March 20th NYC Demo, Bus Letter, 2004
  - Peace, March 20th NYC Demo, Bus Update, 2004
  - Peace, March 20th NYC Demo, Endorsers For, 2004 March 20
  - Peace, March 20th NYC Demo, Flier Major Protest In New York City, 2004 March 20
  - Peace, Military Counter, 2004
  - Peace, More Links, 2003
  - Peace, No Child Left Behind Letter, 2003
  - Peace, November 15th Phone List, 2004
  - Peace, NY Times Article On FBI Spying, 2004
  - Peace, October 25th Rally, Intro Email, 2003
  - Peace, October 25th Rally, Saturday October 25th Flier, 2003
  - Peace, October 25th Rally, Saturday October 25th Flier 2, 2003
  - Peace, On March 5th, 2003
  - Peace, Oskar School Admin Letter, 2004
  - Peace, Oskar School Admin Letter 2, 2004
  - Peace, PBI Fall Speaking Tour Information, 2003
  - Peace, Peace Action, Additional Ad Names, 2002
  - Peace, Peace Action, Faceflier 1, 2003
  - Peace, Peace Action, Faceflier 2, 2003
  - Peace, Peace Action, Faceflier 3, 2003
  - Peace, Peace Action, FCNL Letter, 2003
  - Peace, Peace Action, Mailing, 2003
  - Peace, Peace Action, Peace Action Ad Names, 2002
  - Peace, Peace Action, Peace Action Letter, 2002
  - Peace, Peace Action, Peace Action Phone List, Undated
  - Peace, Peace Action, Seeking A Better Way Ad Text, 2002
  - Peace, Peace Action, Sue DuBois Letter, 2003
  - Peace, Peace Action Minutes, 2004
  - Peace, Petition To End Injustice In Palestine, 2002
  - Peace, Phone Banking Script, 2004 February 15
  - Peace, Protest Flyer, 2004
  - Peace, Reminders What Needs To Be Done, David Scaringe Albany Police Department, 2004
  - Peace, SPAN NY, SPAN Contact Letter, 2003
  - Peace, Spanish March 20th Flier, 2004
  - Peace, SPANsters And Friends, 2003
  - Peace, Spring Semester To Do List, 2003
  - Peace, Student Panel, 2003
  - Peace, SUNY Email Contact & Ironweed, 2004
  - Peace, Urgent Call SPAN Endorse, 2003
  - Peace, Urgent Call Handout, 2003
  - Peace, Vigil For Peace Flyer, 2003
  - Peace, Warning Joining The Military Is Hazardous To, Undated
  - Peace, Weekly Vigil For Peace Flyer, 2003
  - Peace, What The F Am I Doing Here Picture, 2004
  - Prison Work, Drop The Rock Endorsers, 2001
  - Prison Work, DTR Talking Points With Graphics, 2001
  - Prison Work, DTR Voter Registration Fact Sheet, 2001
  - Prison Work, DTR Voter Registration Pledge, 2001
  - Prison Work, How You Can Help Repeal RDLs, Undated
  - Prison Work, Panafrica, 2003
  - Prison Work, Sample Letter, 2001
  - Racism, Action Ideas, 2002
  - Racism, Action Ideas To Fight Racism, 2003
  - Racism, Action Ideas To Fight Racism, 2004
  - Racism, Conference On Eliminating Racism, 2002
  - Racism, DTR Fact Sheet, 2004
  - Racism, Free Mumia Abu, 2002
  - Racism, Reparations Flyer 2, 2004
  - Racism, Reparations Statement, 2004
  - Racism, STAR, Anti-Racism Task Force Contact List, 2002
  - Racism, STAR, Anti-Racist Task Force List, 2002
  - Racism, STAR, Drop The Rock Day Large Flier, 2002
  - Racism, STAR, Drop The Rock Demo Flier, 2002
  - Racism, STAR, Drop The Rock Qtr Fliers, 2002
  - Racism, STAR, Drop The Rock Qtr Fliers Back, 2002
  - Racism, To Get Information On The Reparations Movement, 2004
  - Racism, What Is Racism, 2004
  - Sweatshops, Brown Code, 2003
  - Sweatshops, Sweatshop Coalition, 2003